# MKN Kumar

#### **Chief Executive Officer**

mknkumarceo@gmail.com

(+91) 879-238-7826

linkedin.com/in/mkn-kumar-ceo

#### **Professional Profile**

Skilled Entrepreneur as Managing Director with proven abilities across all levels of organizational management with commitment to excellence having more than 20+ years of experience at different Organizations with remarkable decision-making and multi-tasking abilities. Innovative and driven with strong technical background with natural leadership talent, analytical and problem-solving expertise. Strengths in strategic planning, efficiency and team building. Offering excellent judgment, strong listening skills and a deep understanding of business operations.

# **Work Experience**

#### **CEO & Managing Director**

May 2011 – July 2021 Astroshakthi Productions, Bangalore, KA

- Action-oriented, entrepreneurial, adaptable and innovative approach to business planning passion, idealism, integrity, positive attitude, mission-driven and self-directed.
- Experience in building the Company by increasing its assets and operations, developing its personnel and helping to set & attain business goals and objectives.
- Aligned organizational objectives with Company mission, increasing revenue, profit and business growth by collaboratively developing integrated strategies.

- Strategic planning, assess its structure, operations, policies, staffing, business model and funding requirements and make adjustments as appropriate.
- Comfort in managing various tasks simultaneously, ranging from the strategic to administrative, with proven ability to synthesize, prioritize and act.
- Experience in developing, planning and implementing successful strategies.
- Experience in marketing, sales, finance, HR, performance management principles, public relations and fundraising.
- Developed innovative sales and marketing strategies to facilitate business expansion.
- In-depth knowledge to read analyzes and interprets financial reports and legal documents.
- Experience in preparing all and any kind of legal documents as per the requirement.
- Responsible for the procurement and maintenance of & accounting for all working capital, merchandise and equipment of the Company.
- Developed strategies to build talent, by establishing programs and support systems for the recruitment, hiring, training, evaluation, retention and succession planning for all employees of the Company.
- Interviewed, supervised and motivated all staff members to achieve optimal productivity.
- Developed and maintained a positive relationship with funders, donors, policymakers, colleagues and anyone else who would have an impact on the life of the organization.
- Manages business operations with an emphasis on implementing initiatives to increase profits through performance and future-focused productivity improvements.
- Ability to maximize services with limited resources along with effective budget planning.
- Ensure the organization's complicity with legal and business ethics.

- Drove performance initiatives, facilitating 90% revenue increase.
- Negotiated a Business deal worth of \$100 Millions in favor of Company.

#### **CEO & Managing Director**

July 2009 – May 2011 KSN Properties, Bangalore, KA

- Strategic thinker with an entrepreneurial spirit, capable of moving a small organization to new levels.
- Managed and led team of 25 employee's focused on improving sales initiatives.

- Work collaboratively with the staff to develop and implement programs to achieve organizational goals.
- Strengthen and creatively leverage the use of technology in all aspects of the organization's work.
- In depth knowledge of all rules and regulations about different properties in state.
- Generate and manage lists of properties for sale.
- Perform comparative market analysis to estimate properties value.
- Promote sales through news paper advertisements and listing properties on internet.
- Provide information regarding legal, guidelines, rates, specifications and property availability to customers.
- Intermediate negotiation processes between seller and buyer, ensuring a fair and honest dealing.
- Provide guidance and assist sellers and buyers in marketing and purchasing property for the right price under the best terms & conditions.
- Responsible for compliance with all Company policies and regulatory agencies.

 Increased business profits upto 80% by streamlining processes and trimming unnecessary positions.

#### **CEO & Managing Director**

Sept 2006 – July 2009 Ramanashree Infosystems, Bangalore, KA

- Develop technical training courses for all levels (beginner, intermediate and advanced).
- Prepare educational material (e.g. design manuals and books).
- Explain the subject in a very easy language and understandable method to the students.
- Familiarity with hiring practices and stages screening, interview, assessment and on boarding.
- Experience in using recruiting software and social networks for recruiting.
- Share job ads on various job websites like LinkedIn, Face book, Monster, Indeed, Naukri and Times jobs.
- Manage all communication with candidates from the moment they apply until they get onboard.

• Trained, Educated for more than 500+ students and have placed them in many Companies.

# **Managing Partner & President**

Feb 2001 – Sept 2006 RGR Infosys, Bangalore, KA

## **Key Qualifications & Responsibilities**

- Develop efficient strategies and business plans for all marketing aspects pricing, advertising, branding and product launching and product promotion etc.
- Assist in organizing of promotional events and traditional or digital campaigns.
- Plan and execute initiatives to reach the target audience through appropriate channels like e-mail & TV etc.
- Generating sales revenue from various sources of marketing efforts.
- Serve as the first point of contact for all customers seeking technical assistance over the phone or email.
- Follow up with clients to ensure their IT systems are fully functional after troubleshooting.
- Manage all on-site installations, repair and maintenance.

## **Key Achievements**

• Increased revenue by over 135% in 5 years time span.

## **Managing Partner**

April 1996 – Feb 2001 RGR Technologies, Bangalore, KA

- Entrepreneurial and Organizational qualities and skills.
- Analyze business requirements of all customers for their new systems, software's and applications needs.
- Build or Assemble custom made Systems, according to customer's requirement.

- Experience in installation, integration and configuring hardware's & software's like printers, network cards, graphic Cards and other peripheral devices etc.
- Assist Customers in solving technical problems when they arise, over the phone or pager.
- Building good relationships with all kinds of vendors and customers.
- Familiarity with various operating systems (e.g. Windows, Windows NT, Windows 2000, Red hat Linux and Unix).

• Increased clientele database by 20% every year, which grew net profits by 30% every year.

#### Education

#### MBA / Master of Business Administration

Dublin University, California, USA

**Completion**: 2005

**Relevant Coursework**: Organization Management, Business Management, Marketing Management, Finance Management, HR Management, Economics, Corporate Finance, Managerial Accounting, Financial Accounting, Financial Analysis, Multinational Accounting, Auditing International Finance and Management Information Systems.

#### **Bachelor of Science**

ABSS College, Delhi University, INDIA

**Graduation**: 2000

## **Skills & Endorsements**

- 1. Organizational
- 2. Business Knowledge & Development
- 3. Business Analysis & Intelligence
- 4. Business Operations & Strategy Planning

- 5. Leadership & Management
- 6. Accounting & Finance Management
- 7. Calculated Risk Management
- 8. Time & Risk Management
- 9. Analytical & Budgeting
- 10. Public & Media Relations
- 11. Training & Scheduling
- 12. Interpersonal & Written Communication
- 13. Critical Thinking & Easily Adaptable
- 14. Decision-Making & Public Speaking
- 15. Negotiation & Presentation
- 16. Problem Solving & Teamwork
- 17. Determination & Conceptual
- 18. Creative Thinking & Planning
- 19. Efficiency & Delegation
- 20. Collaboration

## **Core Skills**

Marketing, Sales, Financial Management, Budgeting, ERP Systems, Supply Chain Management, CRM, HR (HCM), Web Development, HTML, Digital Marketing, Cloud Architecture & Technology, Oracle & Database Management, Windows 7, Red hat Linux, Technical and IT Skills.

#### **Certifications**

- Oracle Certified ERP Master in Manufacturing Oracle University, USA
- Completion 1999
- Grade A+

# Languages

• English, Hindi, Kannada, Tamil and Telugu – *Read, Write and Speak*.

## **Other Activities**

- Movie Producer & Director, Member of Karnataka Film Chamber of Producer's Association.
- Volunteered to build Homeless Shelter. Led a drive to raise donations thru Crowd Funding.